cardinalpath.com 2017-06-06

# Privacy Policy | Cardinal Path

## CARDINAL PATH ONLINE PRIVACY POLICY

Last updated: March 7, 2016

**1. APPLICATION.**

This Privacy Policy (the “Policy”) applies to all online web properties, websites, and other online services owned or operated by Cardinal Path, Inc. and/or Cardinal Path LLC (collectively “Cardinal Path”), including:

a)  The cardinalpath.com website;

b)  The cardinalpath.com/blog/ weblog, or ‘blog’, and its content and comment storage, retrieval, and display systems; and

c)  The training.cardinalpath.com website and e-commerce interface; and

d)  The webanalyticssolutionprofiler.com website and e-commerce interface.

The websites noted above will be referred to collectively as “Online Properties”.

**2.   DEFINITIONS.**

For the purposes of this Policy:

a)  “Personally Identifiable Information”, or “PII”, is defined as any piece or  
collection of information or data that can be used to identify an individual, or can  
be related, whether processed or unprocessed, to an individual to find personal  
characteristics, preferences, or other private information which would reveal their  
identity;  
b)  “Confidential Information” is defined as any piece or collection of information or  
data that could reveal commercially or personally sensitive information about an  
organization, corporation, business, or individual which, if revealed, could cause  
irreparable harm to that organization, corporation, business, or individual.

**2.  GENERAL POLICIES REGARDING INFORMATION COLLECTION AND USAGE.**

Cardinal Path takes their visitors’, users’, and clients’ privacy extremely seriously, and considers it an essential part of their commitment to corporate integrity and responsibility to ensure that Personally Identifiable Information and Confidential Information, is safeguarded, kept secure, and never used for purposes other than those which were explicitly stated and consented to at the time of collection.

Cardinal Path does not and will not create software, adapt other software, or otherwise take any action that will facilitate the collection of Personally Identifiable Information or Confidential Information from its visitors without informing the visitor that the information is being collected and the reason and/or purpose for the collection of the information, and acquiring the visitor’s consent to collect and use such information in the manner so described.  Where such a purpose is stated, Cardinal Path will not use the collected Personally Identifiable Information for any purpose other than that stated in advance of the collection of that information.  Cardinal Path understands that the usage of information for a purpose other than that stated, and upon whose basis consent was originally given, shall be considered not to have been consented to by the organization, corporation, business, or individual which provided such information.

Any Personally Identifiable Information or Confidential Information collected by Cardinal Path with the visitor’s consent will be secured and safeguarded according to digital analytics industry best-practices, and will not be made generally available.

Personally Identifiable Information or Confidential Information may be selectively disclosed where that  disclosure is required as a result of any requirements imposed by applicable national or sub-jurisdictional (ie. province or state) law or regulation, court order or other legal process, or enforceable and reasonable government request.

**3.  POLICIES REGARDING INFORMATION COLLECTION SPECIFIC TO INDIVIDUAL PLATFORMS OR TOOLS.**

a)   _Google Analytics_ is a web-based service which assists website owners and operators in learning about and understanding the usage patterns of visitors who use their websites by collecting information about which individual webpages were visited, how long users visited the website, which websites referred the most visitors, general geographic location of visitors and other similar anonymous statistics.

In order to distinguish one visit from another, Google Analytics may create several tracking cookies on a visitor’s computer which will expire after two years have passed since the initial visit.

Google explicitly and expressly forbids the collection of Personally Identifiable Information in the Terms of Service for Google Analytics, and as such Cardinal Path has not attempted to make, has not made, and will never make modifications that would enable Google Analytics or any of the Cardinal Path Online Properties to collect any such information.  Google Analytics does not collect any Personally Identifiable information by default.  Google Analytics collects the Internet Protocol (“IP”) addresses of computers or Internet connections used by visitors to websites on which Google Analytics has been installed. Google Analytics does not reveal or expose the Internet Protocol addresses of visitors to the owners of the website on which Google Analytics is installed.

For additional details on Google’s own Privacy Policy, please visit http://www.google.com/intl/en/policies/privacy/.

b)   _Google AdWords and Remarketing_

_Google AdWords Remarketing_ is a web-based service relying on the _Google Display Network_ which improves the relevance of online advertisements to website visitors where those websites display advertisements from the _Google Display Network_.

In order to distinguish one visitor from another, Google AdWords may create several tracking cookies on a visitor’s computer.  Cardinal Path will only permit such cookies corresponding to remarketing lists for Cardinal Path services to be created on a visitor’s computer when that visitor has visited a section or webpage on a Cardinal Path Online Property that can reasonably be determined to be related to the services to be advertised using the Remarketing feature of Google AdWords.

Google explicitly and expressly forbids the collection of Personally Identifiable Information in the Terms of Service for Google AdWords, and as such, Cardinal Path has not attempted to make, has not made, and will never make modifications that would enable Google AdWords or any of the Cardinal Path Online Properties to collect any such information.

Cardinal Path does not have access, and will never seek access, to information on other websites visitors have visited or which remarketing lists they are on, apart from the Online Properties and remarketing lists of Cardinal Path itself.

For additional details on Google’s own Privacy Policy, please visit http://www.google.com/intl/en/policies/privacy/.

c)   _Contact Form_

The Contact Form on the cardinalpath.com website provides a means for visitors to contact Cardinal Path in order to request more information about Cardinal Path’s services, career opportunities, or other matters.

Information submitted by a visitor using the Contact Form will only be used for the following:

i)  To contact the visitor for the purposes of providing them a reply to their  
request;

ii)  To collect the information in a sales lead database _only_ if the contact form submission was submitted with regard to a potential purchase of services from Cardinal Path; or

iii)  Archived and/or processed for statistical purposes, in which case the information will be stripped of any traceable Personally Identifiable Information or Confidential Information before any statistical or other analysis is undertaken.

In cases where information is entered into a sales lead database, Cardinal Path  
uses NetSuite CRM software for these purposes.

For more information on NetSuite’s own Privacy Policy, please visit http://www.netsuite.com/portal/privacy.shtml.

d)   _Cardinal Path Blog Comments_

The Cardinal Path Blog permits visitors to comment on blog posts written by Cardinal Path staff or other authors in order to provide insight, request more information, or to clarify points made in the blog.

The information provided by a visitor in submitting a comment on a Cardinal Path Blog article will only be used for the following:

i)  To identify the visitor’s comment uniquely and separately from the comments of other individuals;

ii)  In order to display the comment itself in conjunction with the blog article with which it is associated; or

iii)  Archived and/or processed for statistical purposes, in which case the information will be stripped of any traceable Personally Identifiable Information or Confidential Information before any statistical or other analysis is undertaken.

Cardinal Path uses Disqus blog comment management software in order to facilitate the storage and publishing of blog comments for the Cardinal Path Blog.

For additional details on Disqus’ own Privacy Policy, please visit http://help.disqus.com/customer/portal/articles/466259-privacy-policy.

e)   _Case Study Information Form_

The Case Study Information Form on the cardinalpath.com website is intended to collect information regarding potential sales leads who may be evaluating the suitability of Cardinal Path and its services by viewing and downloading PDF-formatted Case Studies.

Information submitted by a visitor in order to download such a Case Study will only be used for the following:

i)  To contact the visitor for the purposes of determining their satisfaction with the contents of the case study;

ii)  To contact the visitor for the purposes of exploring potential opportunities whereby Cardinal Path services may benefit the visitor;

iii)  To collect the information in a sales lead database for the purposes of organizing and expediting the purposes set forth in i) and ii); or

iv)  Archived and/or processed for statistical purposes, in which case the information will be stripped of any traceable Personally Identifiable Information or Confidential Information before any statistical or other analysis is undertaken.

f)   _Career Application Form_

The Career Application Form on the cardinalpath.com website provides a means for visitors to inquire about and submit applications and resumes in response to Cardinal Path career opportunities posted in the Careers section of the cardinalpath.com website.

Information submitted by a visitor using the Career Application Form will only be used for the following:

i)  To contact the visitor for the purposes of providing them further information regarding the status or suitability of their career application, the career opportunity itself, or Cardinal Path as a potential workplace;

ii)  To collect the information in a human resources file or database to aid in the evaluation of applicants for Cardinal Path career opportunities; or

iii)  Archived and/or processed for statistical purposes, in which case the information will be stripped of any traceable Personally Identifiable Information or Confidential Information before any statistical or other analysis is undertaken.

g)   _Online Analytics Maturity Model_ and _Google Analytics Self-Assessment_

The Online Analytics Maturity Model and Google Analytics Self-Assessment Forms on the cardinalpath.com website collect general information with regard to a visitor’s business organization through an optional user-directed form completion process.  In return, the visitor is presented with an automated evaluation of their organization’s analytics practices and/or the soundness of their technical online analytics implementation.

The information collected through the Online Analytics Maturity Model and the Google Analytics Self-Assessment will only be used for the following:

i)  To produce the automated evaluation report mentioned in the previous paragraph; or

ii)   Archived and/or processed for statistical purposes, in which case the information will be stripped of any traceable Personally Identifiable Information or Confidential Information before any statistical or other analysis is undertaken.

Cardinal Path may use FluidSurveys online survey deployment and management software in order to facilitate one or both of the Online Analytics Maturity Model and Google Analytics Self-Assessment.

For more information on FluidSurveys’ own Privacy Policy, please visit http://fluidsurveys.com/about/privacy/.

h)   _Cardinal Path Training Purchases_

In order to process Cardinal Path Training Purchases, some Personally Identifiable Information, such as name, e-mail address, home or business address, phone number, and credit card number, will be collected in order to complete the transaction.  Such information will only be used for these purposes, and will never be correlated with other collected data in order to link other anonymous information to the Personally Identifiable Information collected for the purposes of the transaction.

Cardinal Path may archive and store the previously-noted Personally Identifiable Information (but not the credit card number) for purchaser authentication and management purposes in a way by which Cardinal Path employees will be able to access such information remotely at Cardinal Path Training events in order to authenticate the paid status and identity of attendees.

Cardinal Path uses Google Drive and Box to facilitate such storage and remote access. For additional details on Google’s own Privacy Policy, please visit http://www.google.com/intl/en/policies/privacy/.  For additional details on Box’s own Privacy Policy, please visit https://www.box.com/static/html/privacy.html.

Cardinal Path may use online transaction processing software or services in order to facilitate, process, and complete these transactions.

i)  _Emails_

Email campaigns will be used help identify visitor preferences to improve the user experience, and to better understand customer needs. By using this site you agree to having your historical web browsing activity connected to your email address, company, and other personal information. If you prefer to remain anonymous and untracked, Cardinal Path will respect your rights in this regard, and you may choose to opt-out of tracking here: https://tools.google.com/dlpage/gaoptout

**4.  REVISIONS AND UPDATES TO POLICY**

Due to the nature of this Policy and the Internet, Cardinal Path will not be able to contact individuals who have visited the website individually in order to notify them of changes to the Policy.  However, the most recent version of the Policy will be made continuously available, barring unforeseen technical issues, at the Privacy Policy webpages for each of the Online Properties owned and operated by Cardinal Path, and the most recent revision date will be posted on each such instance of the Privacy Policy.

**5.  CARDINAL PATH CONTACT INFORMATION**

A Cardinal Path representative can be contacted with questions, comments, or suggestions regarding the Cardinal Path Privacy Policy through the Contact Form on the cardinalpath.com website at http://www.cardinalpath.com/contact/.

Cardinal Path can also be contacted by phone at 480.285.1622.

Cardinal Path can be contacted by postal mail in the United States at:

Cardinal Path LLC  
RE: Online Privacy Policy  
301 W. Warner Rd., Suite 136  
Tempe, AZ 85284 US

Cardinal Path can be contacted by postal mail in Canada at:

Cardinal Path, Inc.  
RE: Online Privacy Policy  
1080 Howe St., Suite 503  
Vancouver, BC V6Z 2T1 Canada

## Copyright

Cardinal Path Inc. (hereafter “Cardinal Path”) maintains its website as a service to the Internet community. Access to and use of [cardinalpath.com](http://www.cardinalpath.com/ "Cardinal Path") is subject to the terms and conditions set forth herein and all applicable laws. Cardinal Path may revise these terms and conditions from time to time by updating this posting.

This site and all of its contents including, but not limited to, all text and images (“content”) are owned and copyrighted by Cardinal Path or others with all rights reserved unless otherwise noted. The content, without the express written permission of Cardinal Path or the rightful owner, may not be distributed, downloaded, modified, edited, reused, reproduced, transmitted, performed, displayed or otherwise used by any mechanical or electronic means, except as provided herein.

Any content that is a trademark, logo, or service mark is also a registered and/or unregistered trademark of Cardinal Path or others, including, but not limited to, CARDINAL PATH™, PUBLICINSITE™, CROWDSENSE™, and COMPASS DESIGN.
